A Guide to the Crowder Family Papers, 1876-1976 (bulk 1920-1960)
Library of Virginia
- Series III. Crowder Brothers Store Records, 1912-1954., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 30-32)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1937. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1954. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, n.d.. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Designer Publishing Company. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Dun & Bradstreet. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Insurance. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Lease. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Monthly Store Accounts, 1934-1935. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Promissory Notes. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Sales Literature. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Tax Tickets, Receipts, Forms. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Ledgers and Account Books. (Box 32)
- Series IV. Microbiology Files, 1927-1945., Extent: 1 box. (Box 33)
  The microbiology files relate to Elizabeth (Crowder) Vaill's work as a teacher and researcher with the Connecticut Department of Health. They include class notes, research, and lectures, correspondence (mainly relating to applications for employment in various laboratories in New York), forms, licenses, publications, and reports.
  - Class Notes. (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Forms. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Lab Notes. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Licences. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Publications. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Reports. (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
- Series V. Real Estate Broker Files, 1953-1964., Extent: 1 box. (Box 34)
  The real estate broker files detail Elizabeth (Crowder) Vaill Harlow's work with the firm Harold C. Wiswall Real Estate in Wellesley Hills, Massachussetts. She was the company's representative in the Framingham Centre area. This series contains client files, classified ads, commissions, correspondence, deeds and agreements, photographs, plats, and property listings.
  - Atchley, Dana W., Jr. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Classified Ads. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Commissions. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1964. (Box 34, Folder 4-14)
  - Correspondence, n.d.. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Cote, Paul (Casper, WY). (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Deeds and Agreements. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Gardner, Alfred. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Haley, Priscilla L.. (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Hunt, James G.. (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - LaBorie, G. Walter. (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Mitchell, Robert J.. (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Photographs. (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Plats. (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Previews. (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Property Listings. (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Winch, Alice. (Box 34, Folder 28)
- Series VI. Publications., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 35-36)
  There are two boxes of publications relating to conservation and horticulture, religion, and education.
  - Publications. (Box 35-36)
- Series VII. Newspapers., Extent: 1 box. (Box 37)
  There is one box of newspapers, mostly from colleges and universities, including the North Carolina College for Women.
  - The Carolinian (North Carolina College for Women), 1925-1927, 1936. (Box 37)
  - The Chronicle (Duke University), 11 May 1927. (Box 37)
  - Hampden-Sydney Tiger, 12 and 19 February 1927. (Box 37)
  - South Hill Enterprise, 1927 (April-May). (Box 37)
  - The Union Star (Brookneal, VA), 12 February 1932. (Box 37)
  - The Virginia Tech, 25 February 1926. (Box 37)
  - The Yellow Journal (University of North Carolina), 13 May 1927. (Box 37)